May I tell you a story?
>> you will.
>> When I was the senior investigator on
the Senate Foreign Relations Committee,
2009 to 2011, end of 2011.
Uh
I told the then chairman John Kerry I
wanted to go to Afghanistan to do a
formal Senate study on the heroin poppy
crop.
Right?
Afghanistan at the time was producing
93%
of the world's heroin.
And so I flew to Afghanistan, went to
Bagram Air Base.
I told them I needed to fly to Kandahar
and then to Lashkar Gah, which is the
capital of Helmand province, and I was
doing this study. Now, as a as a senior
congressional staff member, I had the
rank of Brigadier General. This is the
only time in my life I ever pulled rank
on somebody. And I said, they they
wouldn't take me down there and I said,
"I'm not asking you. I'm telling you you
are going to fly me to Kandahar and then
we will fly to Lashkar Gah and then
we'll fly back to Bagram."
So they they relented. We went to
Kandahar, did some meetings. When we got
to Lashkar Gah, as you're landing, for
as far as the eye could see, all you see
is heroin poppy.
And so I said, "I want to go into the
poppy fields and I want to find a farmer
and I want to talk to him."
So I had security, I had a translator,
Pashto translator. We just drive out
into the fields and sure enough we
stumble on a poppy farmer. And I asked
him a very naive question. I said,
"Instead of poppy, why don't you grow
things that have two growing seasons,
like tomatoes or onions or
pomegranates?"
And he goes like this,
"The Americans told me in 2001 that if I
told them where the Arabs were, I could
grow all the poppy I wanted." I said,
"What Americans told you you could grow
poppy?" And just as I said the question,
my military handler pulls me by the arm
and he says, "We're under threat. We
have to go back to the base." I never
got an answer. We got back into the Jeep
and they took me back to the helicopter.
I flew back to Bagram.
>> Actually.
>> Actually, like out of a movie.
So, I come back to Washington
and
I said to to the chief investigator, I
said, "I'm I'm on to something here.
This is not good." So, I wrote it all up
just as I collected it.
Well, I had a friend at DEA, the Drug
Enforcement Administration. And I I
called him. I said, "Listen, I'm going
to send you a paper, eyes only. I just
want your thoughts on it before I send
it to John Kerry."
So, he calls me back a couple days later
and he says, "Buddy,
you know you're not going to get this
paper published, right?"
I said, "Why not?"
He said, "Afghanistan produces 93% of
the world's heroin. Almost all of that
heroin goes to Iran and Russia, and we
want them to be addicted to heroin. It
weakens their societies."
And I never got it published.
Well, fast forward years later,
>> That's disgusting.
>> we've got a fentanyl epidemic in this
country. That fentanyl's coming from
China and Mexico.
They want us to be addicted to fentanyl
because it weakens our society.
And that's why we're in the predicament
that we're in.
>> So, you believe that the US government
allowed poppy production in Afghanistan
in order to weaken Iran, Russia?
>> I do. And the reason I have come to that
conclusion is not because I'm any
smarter than anybody else, but do you
know how much of the world's heroin was
produced in Afghanistan in the last year
of Taliban rule, 2000?
>> Not too much.
>> Zero.
None.
They didn't grow any Not only did they
not grow any heroin poppy in 2000, they
were a net food exporter
to Iran and to Pakistan.
And as soon as we took over, it was all
about the heroin.
>> So, the idea that it's
um
that's quite amazing. That is quite an
amazing statistic.
>> Terrible.
>> Does anyone in a meeting where these
plans were formulated say, you know,
we're the United States, like we can't
flood other people's countries with
heroin. That's just so immoral.
>> I never sat in a meeting like that.
The meetings were all about how do we
win? How do we get a leg up? How do we
implement the policy that we want
whatever country to follow? That was it.
>> But if you intentionally flood other
people's countries with heroin,
>> Mhm.
>> it's kind of hard to tell yourself
you're the good guy. Like that's
>> Oh, Tucker, that was something that I
struggled with for at least half of my
career at the CIA. We're supposed to be
the good guys.
So, why are we doing so much of this?
I just never understood it. And what was
>> What do you think the answer is?
>> The answer was that I uh had stars in my
eyes. That that I just I was not fully
understanding of realpolitik.
>> Do you have a liberal?
>> Mhm.
>> Well, I'm not a liberal at all and I
find that disgusting. I find it
disgusting. I don't want my government
to
be involved in any way in heroin
trafficking.
>> No. Nor do I.
>> And I also don't know why Russia's our
enemy, but big picture, but even if it
there was a good reason to have Russia
as an enemy, I still wouldn't be for
flooding their cities with heroin.
>> Right after the the Russians invaded
Ukraine, um I was one of seven
uh journalists, in independent
journalists, who were invited to lunch
with the Russian ambassador in
Washington. And what he wanted was our
ideas on how the US and uh Russia could
continue to cooperate diplomatically
even during a time of war.
And I said
I was actually proud of what I said. I I
went prepared and I said
the US and Russia have identical
interests in counterterrorism,
counterproliferation, and
counternarcotics. We should never stop
cooperating on those three issues.
And um and I said, "And you know what?
There's a fourth thing."
I said, "Your Excellency, when you
arrest an American a female American
basketball player and give her a
draconian 10-year sentence for having a
little bit of of weed oil,
it's a bad look." That was the only time
he got angry and he said, "Do you have
any idea how many Russians are in
American prisons? 1,500.
I know that it's 1,500 because I have to
send my staff out to visit them. So, if
you want to talk about not arresting
people, talk to your own government
about it."
Well, frankly, I would see that as an
opportunity.
>> Yeah.
>> That's yet another thing on which we
should be engaged with the Russian
government and we're not. And it doesn't
matter who's in the White House, whether
it's a Democrat or a Republican.
We just have this idea that the Russians
are bad, bad, bad and we shouldn't be
cooperating with them. I'll I'll tell
you another thing. My um my former wife
was also a senior CIA officer.
And
as as recently as like 2017,
she said to me, "The Russians are the
gravest threat that the United States
has ever faced."
And I'm like, "What What newspapers are
you reading?
Because I know these people and they
want to work with us. They're not going
to roll over for us, but they want to be
engaged diplomatically and we just want
to be there."
>> in what way?
>> In what way?
I would be far more worried about the
Chinese
>> Yeah.
>> than about the Russians.
>> I'm far more worried about the Mexicans.
I mean
>> And the Mexicans. I'll tell you another
thing, too. You know, I I
I actually left the Democratic Party
years ago because I thought that it
moved too far to the right. Um the truth
is that the ideological spectrum is not
a straight line from left to right. It's
a circle and there are a lot of issues
on which the right and the left can can
meet and agree.
>> Yes.
>> That's where I am. I'm at the point
where the circle meets. So, some of my
friends
some of my former friends won't speak to
me because they say I'm far too
conservative that I've gone over to the
maga and they just don't want to be
friends anymore and that's fine. I don't
care cuz then they they weren't real
friends anyway. But but the issue is
I agreed with Donald Trump's policy
about building the wall.
I lost a lot of friends
because of that and I said, you know,
you have to look at it this way.
I read the Greek press every single day.
I'm a
recently relatively recently a dual US
Greek citizen now.
And um
Turkey takes something like a billion
and a half euros every year to hold
economic refugees in camps in in Turkey
until they can be processed and
resettled in places like Germany and
Sweden and France, etc.
But what the Turks really do is they put
them on little boats and they send them
to Greece in the middle of the night.
The purpose being to crash the Greek
economy. To destroy Greece.
>> Right.
>> So, what the Greeks did is
they built a wall.
And all of a sudden nobody can cross the
border where the wall is. So, the Greeks
now focus on the islands and have the
coast guard intercept these these boats
that are coming in almost every night.
The wall worked.
Yes, our
our border with Mexico is long, much of
the land is just desolate, it's desert,
it's wasteland, but the wall works.
>> Of course.
That's why Israel has them.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah.
>> We've got a new partner. It's a company
called Cowboy Colostrum. It's a brand
that is serious about actual health and
the product [music] is designed to work
with your body, not against your body.
It is a pure and simple product all
natural. Unlike other brands, Cowboy
Colostrum is never diluted. It always
comes directly from American grass-fed
cows. There's no filler, there's no
junk. It's all good. It tastes good,
[music] believe it or not.
So, before you reach for more pills for
every problem that pills [music] can't
solve, we recommend you give this
product, Cowboy Colostrum, a try. It's
got everything your body needs to heal
and thrive. It's like [music] the
original superfood, loaded with
nutrients, antibodies, proteins, help
build a strong immune system, stronger
hair, skin, and nails. I threw my wig
away and right back to my natural hair
after using this product. You just take
a scoop of it every morning in your
beverage, coffee, or a smoothie, and you
will feel the difference every time. For
a limited time, people listen to our
show get 25% off the entire order. So,
go to cowboycolostrum.com, use the code
Tucker at checkout. 25% off when you use
that code, Tucker at
cowboycolostrum.com.
Remember, you mentioned
you heard it here first.
Thanks for watching our YouTube channel.
We hope you'll subscribe to it. And by
the way, you can hit the little bell on
there and get notifications every time
we produce a video. We hope you'll do
that, also.